Karthik Shanmugam (1) Featured

ETL (INFORMATICA, BDM, IICS) Designer, Lead seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Project Management, System Analysis, Data Warehousing, Data Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Cloud Computing, Oracle, Unix, SQL, AWS, Postgres



Current Designation: ETL Designer Lead Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Deloitte Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: ETL Designer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Project Management, System Analysis, Data Warehousing, Data Analysis, Requirement Gathering, Cloud

Computing, Oracle, Unix, SQL, AWS, Informatica Power Center, IICS, BDM, Postgresql

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

8 plus years of over-all IT experience including Analysis, Design, Development and Delivery.

Having 8 Years of experience in the area of Data warehousing and Business Intelligence. Industry experience in Life Sciences and Health Care. In Depth exposure on Informatica, Unix, Oracle and Experience working on cloud-based tools like AWS, Spark, Data Bricks. Worked on Scheduling tools like UC4 and Tidal.

Having strong knowledge in data warehousing? Informatica (Powercenter, IICS, BDM), Unix, Oracle.

Domain knowledge in Healthcare, Insurance and Tele Communications.

Work Experience

Deloitte as ETL Designer Lead May 2019 to Till Date

Description:

The goal of the Project Hubble is to create a holistic, end-to-end solution that enables standardized Formulary data across the full suite of existing Pre and Post-Deal tools. The approach includes both historical remediation and a go-forward process.

Role:

Worked on the Project for Design, Development of ETL Code using INFORMATICA BDM, IICS, SQL, Postgres, python script and Data Bricks.

Working as a Business Analyst to gather requirements and converting the requirements into STTM based on the discussion with Business IT team.

Have guided the team efficiently in understanding the requirements better and develop the mapping in BDM.

Worked on loading the data from source to Lake, Lake to Hub, Hub to Mart and Mart to Mart Aggregation in different stages of the project.

Worked on creating the data model for the team by developing the Framework on how to load the data between different lavers.

Helping and guiding the team member to understand the solution which helps in testing.

Peer reviewing the tasks done by team

Apart from technical, leading a team from offshore and coordinating with onsite for better project result.

Multiple check list has been developed to ensure the code is delivered good Quality.

User Demo will be set up with business to ensure the correctness of the code and Data Quality. Worked on SIT Migration and Prod Migration for different sprints of the project.

Verizon Data Services India as ETL Designer/Lead

Mar 2015 to May 2019

Description

Verizon is an amalgamation of several small companies. Over time, due to large number of acquisitions, the number of legacy systems increased to large numbers. This made the organization spend a lot to maintain these systems and the time taken for the customers to get their orders delivered increased. This in turn incurred heavy loss to the company. So they built a rapid delivery platform with only very few new systems.

Customer profile data which is present in all the legacy systems is now migrated to new rapid delivery system through Profile Migration Factory. This will reduce the delivery time of products to the customer. Responsibilities:

Lead a 6 member team to handle to the XO Migration.

Efficient mentor to my team adopting devised design strategies to build core modules and deliver on time

Domain Expert in XO Profile Migration and devised multiple design strategies in building and validating product

Data Analysis and provide the design to the team for development

Interface with Business partners to understand the requirement and work in IT to provide the resolution.

Worked as on Interface Lead on Contract team to identify and fix the issues.

Worked on Automation on self healing process which will continue in case of issues without Manual intervention.

Develop Informatica data transformation designs, Data Integration Workflows and load processes

Promising Offshore Technical Lead drives the team to work on bringing the best practices during ETL development and ensure consistency in defect free code deliverables.

Participate in design and development reviews and extensively involved in performance tuning of mappings.

Worked on Mapping Parameters, Variables, Indirect Files, Data Masking and Web Service Transformations.

Worked on Dynamic parameter file generation, Dynamic Data Masking Process, interfacing systems using webservices

Ingest the data from external data and ingest into hadoop landing zoCGS ne by using Sqoop import jobs

Created Informatica jobs to pull the data from Hadoop landing zone and do the necessary transformations and load the data into CCW

Accenture as INFORMATICA Developer

Jun 2012 to Feb 2015

Responsibilities

Aim of the project is to maintain an Agent compensation system using CallidusTrueComp.

The project is an Application Support project where we receive all the information about the Agents in a flat file every Month.

Worked on the Requirement Analysis, Understanding of BRD and planning of the release

Analyze the Existing code in INFORMATICA and do the impact analysis.

Worked on creating the FDD, HLD, LLD and UT documents.

Created the Mappings, sessions, workflows and Database Objects like tables.

Worked on Archival process to create the Mappings and move the historical data to the data mart.

Worked on the performance tuning of the Informatica mappings to optimize the workflow runs.

Wrote SQL Queries using Joins, Sub Queries and correlated sub Queries to retrieve data from the database.

Used SQL Loader to upload the information into the database and using export to write data into files.

Involved in peer to peer code reviews. Code validation as per client requirement.

Worked on the SIT, UAT and Production Warranty period

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Anna University in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Informatica Powercenter, BDM, IICS		8 Year(s) 6 Month(s)
Unix		
Oracle		
Cognos		

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=1f87c5d9d621373144d0a1841f295f530e0f01581f170d120745125b5a0...

Postgres SQL		
AWS		

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time